# **ANTONIA VILLA**

#### **FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER**

Seattle, WA Antonia.Villa.2012@gmail.com antoniavilla.com

I'm a full stack developer who refuses to believe data visualization's only role is as a scientific tool for data analytics. Before I took the dive into the engineering world, I worked as an analyst by day and an artist by night. I quickly discovered data representation needed a makeover. My work strives to make data more accessible to the people through the interactive, informative visualizations. A piece of art can inspire, impress, and make you think, and so should a good data visualization.

## **SKILLS**

**FRONT END:** HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, React

**BACK END:** Node JS, Python, MongoDB

ANALYTICAL: PostgreSQL, mySQL, Tableau, VBA, Google Analytics

**DESIGN:** Photoshop CS6, Adobe Creative Suite

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **GENERAL ASSEMBLY: Seattle. WA**

Student Projects

Nov 2017 - Mar 2018

- Distribution of Causes of Death
- A visual exploration of hierarchical open source government data using D3
- Techonologies/Libraries: D3, jQuery, Toastr
- Dreamstate
- An interactive application enabling users to undestand the meaning and trends of their dreams over time
- Techonologies/Libraries: Node/Express, React, Recharts, MongoDB
- Interactive Map: WA Counties
- Exploration of mapping open source census geoData using topoJSON files and D3
- Techonologies/Libraries: gGIS (topoISON file creation), Node/Express, SQL, D3
- Develop secure applications using MVC frameworks and deploy to cloud services (Heroku)
- Collaborate on teams using an agile development workflow; collaboration practices in Git

#### **CUSTOMER PORTFOLIOS: Boston, MA**

Marketing Analyst

Jul 2015 - Oct 2017

- Initiated cross functional collaboration between analysts, data architects, and data engineers to turn clients strategic initiatives into accesible/trackable data structures
- Transition static analytical product to an interactive Tableau Story to display composition of client database, develop customer value segmentation, and identify lifecycle marketing opportunities
- Develop and train analyst team on implementation of built in readiness checks for ETL cycles to deploy automated multi-touch Customer Lifecycle Marketing
- Design and maintain online dashboards to present KPIs to internal and external stake holders; included developing data structures, parameters, and dynamic content through SQL and Tableau

### PATIENTS LIKE ME, INC.: Cambridge, MA

**Acquisition Analyst** 

Apr 2014 - Jul 2015

- Develop multivariate ad testing and monitor daily results to optimize cost per acquisition
- Design and implement recruitment project plans including budget structuring, KPI, and ad strategy
- Manage simultaneously projects ranging in scope from 100 acquisitions in one month to 100,000 acquisitions over two years

#### **EDUCATION**

GENERAL ASSEMBLY: Web Development Immersion Certificate

HARVARD EXTENSION SCHOOL: Programming Certificate

HAMILTON COLLEGE: Bachelor of Arts, Mathematics and Fine Arts

May 2012

#### AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

BRA Certified Artist – works currently showing in Metro Boston Area Recipient of Artist Fellowship Grant, Somerville Arts Council